### Emily Asquith

62 Pear Tree Park, Holme, LA6 1PP emily.asquith@icloud.com
07415 511533

#### Personal Statement

I am an experienced and capable software developer, with good knowledge of full stack technologies, particularly HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Python, Django, Java, and C#. I am currently studying with Code Institute to formalise my education in these fields.

I am a fast and able learner, able to pick up skills very quickly by applying conceptual knowledge from other, more familiar, skillsets.

I work excellently in a team, with a collaboration-first mindset, while also having the drive to take on and complete tasks individually.

### Employment and Work Experience

# *eCommerce Executive,* Rock and Road Training & Safety Consultancy May 2021 – present

- Oversaw the development of an eCommerce store for Ride MT, the motorcycle training side of the business.
- Liaised with suppliers to manage our inventory and place purchase orders.
- Took responsibility for all aspects of the websites for both R&R and Ride MT, including design, maintenance, and addition of new content.
- Managed customer relations, dealing with all manner of inquiries for both sides of the business.
- Managed the creation of an EPOS system and catalogue of inventory, and oversaw the creation of the eCommerce store during our director's acquisition of a motorcycle dealer, gear store, and garage.
- Created small command line applications in C# to automate tasks for admin use.

Crew Member, McDonald's Longton April 2019 – December 2019

Sales Team Member, Clarks Shoes Kendal (Outlet) July 2017 – September 2018

Sales Team Member, Clarks Shoes Kendal (Retail) October 2016 – July 2017

#### Education

# *Diploma in Full Stack Software Development,* Code Institute March 2022 – September 2022 (expected)

I am currently studying full stack development with Code Institute in order to formalise my education. The course has a focus on JavaScript, Python, and Django, using Git and GitHub for version control.

Once I have completed the program, I will have a full professional portfolio using these tools.

#### CertHE Computer Science, Staffordshire University September 2018 – May 2019

Distinction

During my time studying at university, I gained experience in many aspects of software development, including using the USDP to design software, and use of Java and C# to create back-end, command line applications.

I learnt how to effectively use Slack and other tools to aid in collaboration and the smooth running of a small team of people, and simultaneously engaged in group projects where communication and close teamwork was essential to the success of the project.

#### Kirkbie Kendal School, Kendal September 2011 – May 2018

A Levels: Maths (A\*); EPQ (A\*); Computer Science (C).

AS Levels: Further Maths (A); General Studies (C).

GCSEs: 10 GCSEs A\*-C, including Maths (A\*) and English (B).

#### Additional Information

- I participated in the April 2022 hackathon hosted by Code Institute, working in a team to develop a website with the prompt of 'Earth Day'.
- I was awarded the Computing Prize for my work throughout Sixth Form at Kirkbie Kendal School.
- I play chess in my spare time, putting significant effort into studying theory and constantly improving my play.

References available on request.